These are dark times,
there is no denying.
지금은
어둠의 시기입니다
Our world has, perhaps, faced no
greater threat than it does today.
역사상 최악의 위협에
직면해 있지요
But I say this to our citizenry.
허나, 시민 여러분께
맹세컨대
We, ever your servants...
우리 마법부는
will continue to
defend your Liberty...
여러분의 자유를
뺏어 가려는
and repel the forces that
seek to take it from you.
어둠의 세력을
반드시 응징할 것입니다
Your Ministry remains...
마법부는 여전히
strong.
강합니다
어둠의 표식
공포를 심다
머글 일가족 몰살
Hermione. Tea's ready, darling.
헤르미온느, 차 마시렴
Coming, Mom.
가요, 엄마
Come on, Dudley, hurry up.
서둘러, 두들리
I still don't understand
why we have to leave.
왜 떠나야 되는데?
Because, unh, it's not
safe for us here anymore.
여긴 우리한테
안전하질 않아
Ron, tell your father
supper's nearly ready.
론, 아빠한테
저녁 드시라고 해
Is this in Australia?
저기 호주야?
Looks wonderful, doesn't it?
응, 아름답지?
Three and a half thousand kilometers
along Australia's east coast.
Obliviate.
오블리비아테
해리 포터와 죽음의 성물 1
Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows: Part 1 (2010)
Severus.
스네이프
I was beginning to worry
you had lost your way.
길을 잃었나
걱정하고 있었지
Come, we've saved you a seat.
앉아, 자리 비워 놨어
You bring news, I trust?
알아냈겠지?
It will happen Saturday
next, at nightfall.
다음 주 토요일
해질녘이랍니다
I've heard differently, my Lord.
전 다르게 들었습니다
Dawlish, the Auror, has let
slip that the Potter boy...
오러에게 듣기론
포터 녀석을
will not be moved until
the 30th of this month.
30일 전엔
안 옮길 거랍니다
The day before he turns 17.
17살 생일 전날이지요
This is a false trail.
거짓 정보를 흘린 겁니다
The Auror Office no longer plays any
part in the protection of Harry Potter.
오러 사무국은
이번 일에 관여하지 않아요
Those closest to him believe we
have infiltrated the Ministry.
그들은 우리가
마법부에 침투했다 믿지요
Well, they got that
right, haven't they?
제대로 알고 있네
What say you, Pius?
파이어스, 자네 생각은?
One hears many things, my Lord.
헛소문과 정보 중에
Whether the truth is
among them is not clear.
진짜를 가리긴
쉽지가 않지요
Heh. Spoken like a
true politician.
정치인답게 둘러 말하는군
You will, I think, prove
most useful, Pius.
앞으로 가장 쓸모가 많겠어
- Where will he be taken, the boy?
- To a safe house.
- 녀석을 어디로 옮기지?
- 은신처인데
Most likely the home of
someone in the Order.
불사조 기사단원의
집이겠지요
I'm told it's been given every
manner of protection possible.
온갖 방어 마법을
쳐 놨다고 하니
Once there, it will be
impractical to attack him.
일단 들어가면
공격은 불가능합니다
Ahem. My Lord. I'd like to
volunteer myself for this task.
어둠의 마왕님
저한테 맡겨 주세요
I want to kill the boy.
제가 죽일게요
웜테일!
Wormtail!
Have I not spoken to you about
keeping our guest quiet?
손님을 조용히 시키랬잖아!
Yes, my Lord.
네, 주인님
Right away, my Lord.
당장 그렇게 합지요
As inspiring as I find your
bloodlust, Bellatrix...
피에 굶주렸겠지만
벨라트릭스
I must be the one
to kill Harry Potter.
해리 포터는
내가 죽여야 한다
But I face an unfortunate
complication.
허나, 유감스럽게도
문제가 있지
That my wand and Potter's
share the same core.
녀석과 내 지팡이는
속이 같은 물질이라
They are, in some ways, twins.
사람으로 치면
쌍둥이와 같다
We can wound, but not
fatally harm one another.
상처를 입힐 순 있어도
죽일 순 없지
If I am to kill him...
놈을 죽이려면
I must do it with
another's wand.
다른 자의 지팡이가 필요해
Come, surely one of you
would like the honor?
이 영광스러운 일에
지원할 자 있나?
Mm?
What about you, Lucius?
자넨 어때, 루시우스?
My Lord?
주인님?
"My Lord?"
"주인님"
I require your wand.
지팡이 내놔
Do I detect elm?
느릅나무인가?
Yes, my Lord.
네, 주인님
And the core?
속은 뭐로 돼 있지?
Dragon. Ahem.
용의…
Dragon heartstring, my Lord.
용의 심장입니다
- Dragon heartstring.
- Mm.
용의 심장
To those of you who
do not know...
오늘 자리를 빛내 준
벌베이지 교수는
we are joined tonight
by Miss Charity Burbage...
who, until recently, taught at Hogwarts
School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
최근까지
호그와트 마법 학교에서
Her specialty was
Muggle Studies.
머글에 대한
모든 걸 가르쳤다
It is Miss Burbage's belief that
Muggles are not so different from us.
순수 혈통인 우리와 머글들이
다를 게 없다고 믿으며
She would, given her way...
우리가 머글들과
have us mate with them.
짝짓기를 바라지
To her, the mixture of magical and
Muggle blood is not an abomination...
마법사와 머글 사이의 잡종을
혐오하기는커녕
but something
to be encouraged.
오히려 장려해 왔다
Severus.
스네이프
Severus, please.
제발…
We're friends.
우린 친구잖아요
Avada Kedavra!
아바다 케다브라
Nagini.
내기니
Dinner.
저녁이다
덤블도어를 기억하며
엘피아스 도지
- Hello, Harry.
- All right. Wow.
- 안녕, 해리
- 왔구나!
Hello.
어서 와
- You're looking fit. - Yeah,
he's absolutely gorgeous.
- 건강해 보이네
- 그래, 참 멋지다
What say we get undercover
before someone murders him?
살해되기 전에 들어가자고
Evening.
안녕하세요
I thought you were looking
after the Prime Minister.
킹슬리, 수상님 경호는요?
You are more important.
네 경호가 더 중요해
- Hello, Harry. Bill Weasley.
- Oh. Pleasure to meet you.
- 안녕, 빌 위즐리야
- 반가워요
- He was never always this handsome.
- Dead ugly.
- 원래는 이렇게 안 멋져
- 완전 못생겼지
True enough.
사실이야
Owe it all to a werewolf,
name of Greyback.
늑대인간한테 당했어
- Hope to repay the favor one day.
- You're still beautiful to me, William.
- 언젠간 빚을 갚아 줄 거야
- 지금 모습도 나한텐 멋져
Just remember, Fleur, Bill takes
his steaks on the raw side now.
이젠 빌도
스테이크를 날로 먹어
My husband, the joker.
우리 남편이 좀 썰렁해요
By the way, wait till you
hear the news. Remus and I...
참, 좋은 소식이에요
우리가 곧…
All right. We'll have time
for a cozy catch-up later.
밀린 얘기는 나중에!
We've got to get the hell
out of here. And soon.
여길 벗어나야 돼
최대한 빨리!
Potter, you're underage, which means
you've still got the Trace on you.
넌 미성년자라
추적 마법에 걸려 있어
What's the Trace?
그게 뭐죠?
If you sneeze, the Ministry
will know who wipes your nose.
네가 기침만 해도
마법부에서 알지
We have to use those means of
transport the Trace can't detect.
추적 마법을 따돌릴
이동 수단을 써야 돼
Brooms, Thestrals and the like.
We go in pairs.
빗자루, 세스트랄 등…
둘씩 짝지어서 가
That way, if anyone's out there waiting
for us, and I reckon there will be...
그래야 놈들이
우리를 습격해 와도
they won't know which Harry
Potter is the real one.
누가 진짜인지 모를 테니까
The real one?
진짜라뇨?
I believe you're familiar
with this particular brew.
폴리 주스 마법약
알지?
No. Absolutely not.
안돼요, 절대 안 돼요
I told you he'd take it well.
싫어할 거랬죠?
No, if you think I'm gonna let
everyone risk their lives for me, I...
나 때문에
모두 위험해지잖아요
- Never done that before, have we?
- No. No. This is different.
- 처음도 아닌 걸, 뭐
- 이건 달라
I mean, taking that,
becoming me. No.
마법약을 먹고
나로 위장하다니!
Well, none of us
really fancy it, mate.
우리도 좋진 않아
Imagine if something went wrong, and we
ended up a scrawny, specky git forever.
잘못되면 평생 깡마른
안경잡이로 살게 되니까
Everyone here is of age, Potter.
우린 다 성인이고
They've all agreed
to take the risk.
위험성을 알고 동의했다
Technically, I've been coerced.
난 싫었는데 강요당했어
Mundungus Fletcher, Mr. Potter.
먼던구스 플레처야
- Always been a huge admirer.
- Nip it, Mundungus.
- 네 광팬이지
- 조용해!
All right, Granger,
as discussed.
헤르미온느, 계획대로 하자
- Blimey, Hermione. - Straight
in here, if you please.
- 헤르미온느!
- 여기 넣어
For those of you who haven't taken
Polyjuice Potion before, fair warning.
처음 마시는 거라면
미리 말하지만
It tastes like goblin piss.
도깨비 오줌 맛이야
Have a lot of experiences
with that, do you, Mad-Eye?
오줌을 자주 마시나 봐요?
Just trying to
diffuse the tension.
긴장 해소용 조크였어요
Oh.
Ugh.
Wow, we're identical.
- 우리가 똑같아졌어!
Not yet, you're not.
아직 아니야
Haven't got anything a bit
more sporting, have you?
좀 세련된 옷 없어요?
I don't really fancy this color.
색깔이 구려요
Well, fancy this, you're not
you. So shut it and strip.
그거 안 됐네, 닥치고 입어
All right, all right.
- 알았어!
- 너도 갈아입어, 포터
You'll need to
change too, Potter.
Bill, look away. I'm hideous.
빌, 쳐다보지 마
너무 끔찍해
I knew she was lying
about that tattoo.
문신 있다더니
지니가 뻥 쳤네
Harry, your eyesight
really is awful.
해리, 너 눈 진짜 나쁘다
Right, then. We'll be pairing off.
Each Potter will have a protector.
각자 포터와
짝을 지어서 간다
Mundungus, stick tight to me.
I wanna keep an eye on you.
먼던구스
넌 나한테 붙어 있어
- As for Harry...
- Yes?
- 해리는…
- 네?
The real Harry.
진짜 해리
- Where the devil are you, anyway?
- Here.
- 어디 있어?
- 여기요
You'll ride with Hagrid.
해그리드랑 가
I brought you here 16 years ago when
you were no bigger than a Bowtruckle.
16년 전 갓난아기인 널
여기 데려왔는데
Seems only right that I should
be the one to take you away now.
이젠 널 데리고 떠나는구나
Yes, it's all very touching.
Let's go.
눈물 나는 스토리네
가자고!
Head for the Burrows.
We'll rendezvous there.
위즐리 집으로 가
거기서 만난다
On the count of three.
셋에 출발해
Hold tight, Harry.
꽉 잡아, 해리
One...
하나
two...
둘
three!
셋!
- Which one?
- Where are you?
- 따라와!
- 어디 있냐?
He's on your right!
네 오른쪽이야!
He's over there!
저기! 쫓아가!
Down!
피해!
Hagrid, we have to
help the others!
도와줘야 돼요
I can't do that, Harry.
Mad-Eye's orders.
그건 안돼
매드아이 지시야
Hang on.
꽉 잡아!
Stupefy!
스투페파이
Hang on, Harry.
꽉 잡아!
Hagrid.
해그리드!
No. No.
안돼!
Harry.
해리
Harry. Hagrid.
해리, 해그리드
What happened? Where
are the others?
어떻게 된 거야?
다른 사람들은?
Is no one else back?
아무도 안 왔어요?
They were on us right from the start,
Molly. We didn't stand a chance.
죽음을 먹는 자들의
습격을 받았어요
Well, thank goodness
you two are all right.
무사해서 다행이에요
The Death Eaters were waiting
for us. It was an ambush.
놈들이 길목을
지키고 있었어요
Ron and Tonks should've
already been back.
론 오빠와 통스가
아직 안 왔어
Dad and Fred as well.
아빠랑 프레드 오빠도
Here!
여기!
Quick. Into the house.
빨리! 안으로 옮겨!
Oh, my boy.
내 아들!
Oh. Oh.
- 루핀!
- 왜 그래요?
- Lupin!
- What are you doing?
What creature sat
in the corner...
네가 호그와트의
내 사무실에
the first time Harry Potter
visited my office in Hogwarts?
처음 왔을 때 구석에
어떤 생물이 있었지?
- Are you mad?
- What creature?!
- 미쳤어요?
- 말해 봐!
A Grindylow.
그라인딜로우
We've been betrayed.
배신자가 있어
Voldemort knew you were
being moved tonight.
볼드모트가 다 알고 있었어
I had to make sure you
weren't an impostor.
네가 진짜인지
확인해야 했다
Wait.
기다려!
The last words Albus Dumbledore
spoke to the pair of us?
덤블도어가 우리한테 남긴
유언이 뭐지?
"Harry is the best hope we have.
Trust him."
"해리가 가장 큰 희망이다
그를 믿어라"
What gave you away?
어쩌다 들켰어?
Hedwig, I think. She was
trying to protect me.
헤드위그 때문에요
절 지켜 주려 따라왔죠
Thanks.
고마워
Deserves that.
Brilliant, he was.
더 안아 줘
아주 용감했었어
- I wouldn't be standing here without him.
- Really?
- 론이 아니었으면 난 여기 없을 거야
- 진짜요?
Always the tone of surprise.
뭘 그런 걸로
놀라고 그래?
We the last back?
다 왔어?
Where's George?
조지는요?
How you feeling, Georgie?
좀 어때, 조지?
Saint-like.
시원해
Come again?
뭐?
Saint-like. I'm holy.
시원하다고, 조크야
I'm holey, Fred. Get it?
귀에 구멍 뚫려서
바람 잘 통한다는
The whole wide world of ear-related
humor and you go for "I'm holey."
기껏 생각해 낸 조크가
그거야?
That's pathetic.
진짜 썰렁하다
Reckon I'm still
better-looking than you.
귀에 구멍 났어도
너보단 잘생겼어
Mad-Eye's dead.
매드아이가 죽었어요
Mundungus took one look at
Voldemort and Disapparated.
볼드모트가 나타나자
먼던구스는 도망쳤고요
Head for the Burrows.
위즐리 집으로 가!
This is beyond
anything I imagined.
- 생각보다 심각해
- 7개?
- Seven?
- Seven...? A Horcrux.
7개? 호크룩스
They could be hidden anywhere.
- 숨겨 놨겠죠?
- 자기 영혼을 7조각 내서…
To rip the soul into
seven pieces...
- If you did destroy each Horcrux...
- One destroys Voldemort.
- 다 파괴하면요?
- 볼드모트가 죽지
Trust me.
날 믿으렴
You lied to me. Lied
to me, Ollivander.
넌 날 속였다, 올리밴더
Going somewhere?
어디 가?
Nobody else is going to die.
Not for me.
날 위해서 또 누군가를
죽게 할 순 없어
For you?
널 위해서?
You think Mad-Eye died for you?
매드아이 죽은 게?
You think George took
that curse for you?
조지 형이 다친 것이?
You may be the Chosen One, mate, but
this is a whole lot bigger than that.
넌 선택된 마법사지만
너만을 위해서가 아니야
It's always been
bigger than that.
우리 모두를 위해서지
- Come with me.
- What, and leave Hermione?
- 같이 가자
- 헤르미온느 두고?
You mad? We wouldn't last
two days without her.
미쳤니? 걔 없으면
우린 이틀도 못 버텨
Don't tell her I said that.
방금 한 말
걔한테는 비밀이야
Besides, you've still
got the Trace on you.
아직 추적 마법 걸려 있잖아
- We've still got the wedding...
- I don't care about a wedding.
- 결혼식도 있고
- 결혼식엔 관심 없어
I'm sorry. No matter whose it is. I
have to start finding these Horcruxes.
네 형의 결혼식이라도…
난 호크룩스를 찾아야 돼
They're our only
chance to beat him...
'그'를 이길
유일한 방법이고
and the longer we stay
here, the stronger he gets.
지체할수록
'그'는 더 강해져
Tonight's not the night, mate.
지금 떠나는 건
We'd only be doing him a favor.
놈한테만 좋은 일이야
Do you think he knows?
'그'가 알까?
I mean, they're bits of his soul,
these Horcruxes. Bits of him.
호크룩스는
'그'의 영혼 조각이잖아
When Dumbledore destroyed the ring,
you destroyed Tom Riddle's diary...
덤블도어가 반지를
네가 일기장을 파괴했을 때
he must have felt something.
뭔가 느꼈을 거야
To kill the other Horcruxes,
we have to find them.
나머지 호크룩스도
파괴해야 할 텐데
Where are they?
어디 있지?
Where do we start?
어디서부터 찾아야 돼?
Ready when you are.
Please pay attention! It's your
brother's wedding. Buck up.
덤블도어의 어두운 비밀
저자: 리타 스키터
덤블도어를 기억하며
엘피아스 도지
Zip me up, will you?
지퍼 좀?
It seems silly, doesn't
it, a wedding?
결혼하는 거
한심하지 않아?
Given everything
that's going on.
이런 상황에서…
Maybe that's the best
reason to have it...
더 나을지도 모르지
because of everything
that's going on.
이런 상황이니까
Morning.
굿모닝
Come on, keep up.
All together now.
전부 동시에!
One, two, three.
하나, 둘, 셋!
How's it looking
at your end, boys?
그쪽 어때?
Brilliant.
좋아요!
Bloody hell. What's the
Minister of Magic doing here?
젠장
마법부 장관이 왜 왔지?
To what do we owe the
pleasure, Minister?
무슨 일이시죠, 장관님?
I think we both know the answer
to that question, Mr. Potter.
내가 왜 왔는지는
자네도 잘 알 거야
And this is...?
뭐죠?
"Herein is set forth the
last will and testament..."
"나, 알버스 퍼시발 울프릭"
of Albus Percival
Wulfric Brian Dumbledore.
"브라이언 덤블도어는
다음과 같이 유언한다"
First, to Ronald
Bilius Weasley...
"론 빌리우스 위즐리에게"
I leave my Deluminator...
"딜루미네이터를 남긴다"
a device of my own making...
"내가 만든 것으로"
in the hope that, when
things seem most dark...
"세상이 어둠으로 뒤덮였을 때"
"...it will show him the light."
"빛을 보여 줄 것이다"
- Dumbledore left this for me?
- Yeah.
- 이걸 제게 남기셨어요?
- 그래
Brilliant.
좋네요
What is it?
근데 뭐죠?
Wicked.
죽인다
"To Hermione Jean Granger..."
"헤르미온느 진 그레인저에겐"
I leave my copy of The
Tales of Beedle the Bard...
"'방랑시인 비들의 이야기'
책을 남기며"
"...in the hope that she find it
entertaining and instructive."
"재미와 교훈을
동시에 얻길 바란다"
Mom used to read me those.
어렸을 때 엄마가 읽어 줬어
"The Wizard and
the Hopping Pot."
"배비티 래비티와
꼬꼬 웃는 그루터기"
"Babbitty Rabbitty and
the Cackling Stump."
Come on, Babbitty Rabbitty.
배비티 래비티 이야기
알잖아?
No?
몰라?
"To Harry James Potter..."
"해리 제임스 포터에겐"
I leave the Snitch he caught in his
first Quidditch match at Hogwarts...
"첫 퀴디치 경기에서 잡은
스니치를 남기며"
as a reminder of the
rewards of perseverance...
"인내와 기술에 대한
보상을 상기시키는"
"...and skill."
"물건이 되길 바란다"
- Is that it, then?
- Not quite.
- 끝이에요?
- 아니
Dumbledore left you
a second bequest.
덤블도어가 네게
다른 유품도 남겼다
The sword of Godric Gryffindor.
고드릭 그리핀도르의 칼
Unfortunately, the sword of Gryffindor
was not Dumbledore's to give away.
하지만 덤블도어가
줄 수 있는 게 아니야
As an important historical
artifact, it belongs...
역사적인 유물로서
그 칼의 주인은…
To Harry.
해리죠
It belongs to Harry.
해리 거예요
It came to him when he needed
it in the Chamber of Secrets.
비밀의 방에서
찾아냈잖아요
The sword may present itself
to any worthy Gryffindor.
그 칼이 해리 앞에
나타났다고 해서
That does not make it
that wizard's property.
해리의 것이 되는 건 아니다
And, in any event, the current
whereabouts of the sword are unknown.
현재로선
그 칼의 행방도 알 수 없고
- Excuse me?
- The sword is missing.
- 네?
- 사라졌네
I don't know what you're
up to, Mr. Potter...
계획이 뭔진 모르지만
포터 군
but you can't fight
this war on your own.
자네 혼자
'그'와 싸울 순 없어
He's too strong.
'그'는 아주 강력해
Hello, Harry.
안녕, 해리
I've interrupted a deep thought, haven't I?
I can see it growing smaller in your eyes.
생각하는 데 방해됐구나?
눈빛이 그래
Of course not. How
are you, Luna?
- 잘 지냈어, 루나?
- 응
Very well. Got bitten by a
garden gnome only moments ago.
땅신령한테 물린 것만 빼고
Gnome saliva is very beneficial.
땅신령 침은 몸에 좋은 거야
Xenophilius Lovegood. We
live just over the hill.
제노필리우스 러브굿이다
Pleasure to meet you, Sir.
반갑습니다
I trust you know, Mr. Potter,
that we at The Quibbler...
우리 잡지
'이러쿵 저러쿵'은
unlike those toadies
at The Daily Prophet...
'예언자 일보'의
아첨꾼들하곤 달라
fully supported Dumbledore
in his lifetime...
생전 덤블도어를
지지해 왔고
and, in his death,
support you just as fully.
지금은 널 지지한다
Thank you.
감사합니다
Come, Daddy. Harry doesn't
want to talk to us right now.
가요, 아빠
지금 말하기 싫은데
He's just too polite to say so.
너무 착해서
받아 주는 거예요
Harry Potter.
해리 포터
Excuse me, Sir? May I sit down?
실례해요, 앉아도 될까요?
Mr. Potter. By all means. Here.
포터 군
물론이지, 앉게
Thanks.
감사합니다
I found what you wrote in The
Daily Prophet really moving.
'예언자 일보' 기사는
감동적이었어요
You obviously knew
Dumbledore well.
덤블도어와 친구셨나요?
Well, I certainly
knew him the longest.
가장 오랫동안 알고 지냈지
That is, if you don't count
his brother, Aberforth...
그의 형제인
애버포스를 빼면…
and somehow, people never
do seem to count Aberforth.
사람들은 항상
그를 빼놓지만
- I didn't even know he had a brother.
- Ah.
형제가 있는지 몰랐네요
Well, Dumbledore was always
very private, even as a boy.
그 친구, 어려서부터
비밀이 많았지
Don't despair, Elphias.
걱정 말아요, 엘피아스 도지
I'm told he's been thoroughly
unriddled by Rita Skeeter...
리타 스키터가
800페이지에 걸쳐
in 800 pages, no less.
그의 삶을 파헤친
책을 썼으니까
Word has it that
someone talked to her.
그의 비밀들을 누설한
사람이 있대요
Someone who knew the
Dumbledore family well.
덤블도어 가문을
잘 아는 사람
Both you and I know
who that is, Elphias.
그게 누군진
당신도 잘 알 거예요
A monstrous betrayal.
그런 배신을 하다니!
Who are we talking about?
누군데요?
Bathilda Bagshot.
바틸다 백셧
- Who?
- My God, boy...
- 누구요?
- 몰라?
she's only the most celebrated
magical historian of the last century.
지난 세기의 가장 뛰어난
마법 역사가인데
She was as close to the
Dumbledores as anyone.
덤블도어 가문과
아주 친하게 지냈어
Oh, I'm sure Rita Skeeter thought it
well worth a trip to Godric's Hollow...
리타 스키터가
고드릭 골짜기까지 찾아가
to take a peek into that
old bird's rattled cage.
노망난 할망구한테
캐물은 게 틀림없어
Godric's Hollow?
그 할머니가
Bathilda Bagshot lives
at Godric's Hollow?
고드릭 골짜기에 살아요?
Well, that's where she
first met Dumbledore.
거기서 덤블도어를
처음 만났어
You don't mean to say
he lived there too?
덤블도어도
거기 살았다고요?
The family moved there after his
father killed those three Muggles.
그의 아버지가
머글 셋을 죽인 후에 이사했지
Oh, it was quite the scandal.
당시엔
엄청난 스캔들이었어
Honestly, my boy, are you
sure you knew him at all?
덤블도어에 대해
잘 모르는구나?
The Ministry has fallen.
마법부가 무너졌고
The Minister of Magic is dead.
스크림저 장관은 죽었다
They are coming.
그들이 몰려온다
They're coming!
Nice meeting you, Mr. Potter.
반가웠네, 포터 군
- Ginny!
- Harry! Go!
- 지니!
- 도망쳐!
Go!
가!
Here you go, sightseeing tour?
Leaves in 15 minutes.
시내 관광버스가
15분 후 출발해요
- Where are we?
- Shaftesbury Avenue.
- 어디야?
- 셰프츠뷰리 가
I used to come to the theater
here with Mom and Dad.
여기 극장에 자주 왔었어
I don't know why I thought of it.
It just popped into my head.
이유는 몰라도
여기를 생각했어
This way.
이쪽이야
We need to change.
옷 갈아입어야 돼
How the ruddy...?
어떻게…
Undetectable Extension Charm.
탐지 불능 늘이기 마법이야
You're amazing, you are.
넌 정말 대단해
Always the tone of surprise.
뭘 그런 걸로
놀라고 그래?
Ah. That'll be the books.
책 떨어지는 소리야
What about all the
people at the wedding?
결혼식에 있던 사람들은?
- Do you think we should go back?
- They were after you.
- 돌아가야 할까?
- 널 노리잖아
We'd put everyone in
danger by going back.
돌아가면 다 위험해져
- Ron's right.
- Ahem.
론이 옳아
Coffee?
커피?
- A cappuccino, please.
- You?
- 카푸치노요
- 그쪽은?
- What she said.
- Same.
- 얘가 시킨 거요
- 나도요
So where do we go from here?
Leaky Cauldron?
이제 어디로 가지?
리키 콜드런 클럽?
It's too dangerous.
너무 위험해
If Voldemort has taken over the Ministry,
none of the old places are safe.
볼드모트가
마법부를 장악했다잖아
Everyone from the wedding will have
gone underground, into hiding.
결혼식에 왔던
손님들도 다 숨을 거야
My rucksack with all my things,
I've left it at the Burrow.
젠장! 배낭을 놔두고 왔어
You're joking.
진짜야?
I've had all the essentials
packed for days, just in case.
필요한 건 다 챙겨 놨었어
혹시 몰라서…
By the way, these
jeans, not my favorite.
그건 그렇고
이 청바지 별로야
Down!
엎드려!
Stupefy!
스투페파이
Expulso!
엑스펄소
Petrificus Totalus.
페트리피쿠스 토탈루스
Go.
가요
Leave.
나가요!
Lock the door, get the lights.
문 잠그고 불 꺼
This one's name is Rowle.
이름은 라울
He was on the Astronomy Tower the
night Snape killed Dumbledore.
덤블도어가 살해될 때
천문탑에 있었어
This is Dolohov. I recognize
him from the wanted posters.
돌로호브야
수배 전단에서 봤어
So, what we gonna
do with you, hey?
널 어떻게 할까?
Kill us if it was turned
round, wouldn't you?
너라면 우리를 죽이겠지?
If we kill them, they'll
know we were here.
- 죽이면 놈들한테 들켜
- 론
Ron.
Suppose he did Mad-Eye.
How would you feel then?
매드아이를 죽인 게
이놈이라면?
It's better we wipe
their memories.
기억을 지우자
You're the boss.
네가 대장이니까…
Hermione...
헤르미온느
you're the best at spells.
주문은 네 전문이잖아
Obliviate.
오블리비아테
How is it they knew
we were there?
우리를 어떻게 찾아냈을까?
Maybe you still have
the Trace on you?
- 네가 추적 마법에 걸려 있다면?
- 아냐, 17살이 되면
Can't be. Trace breaks at 17.
It's wizarding law.
자동으로 깨지잖아
What?
왜?
We didn't celebrate
your birthday, Harry.
네 생일 파티 못 했잖아
Ginny and I, we prepared a cake.
지니랑 내가
케이크 만들었어
We were going to bring it out
at the end of the wedding.
결혼식 끝나고
하려고 했는데
I appreciate the thought, but given the
fact that we were almost killed...
생각은 고맙지만 조금 전에
죽음을 먹는 자들한테
by a couple of Death
Eaters a few minutes ago...
죽을 뻔했거든?
Right.
하긴…
Perspective.
알았어
We need to get off the
streets, get somewhere safe.
일단 안전한 곳으로 가자
What was that all about?
뭐였어?
Probably Mad-Eye's idea, in case
Snape decided to come snooping.
매드아이의 아이디어겠지
스네이프를 막기 위한…
Homenum Revelio.
호메눔 레벨리오
We're alone.
우리뿐이야
I believed another wand-
다른 지팡이로는 죽일 수…
You lied to me. It
makes no sense.
- 날 속였어
- 이해가 안 돼
I believed a different
wand would work, I swear.
그거라면 해리를
죽일 수 있었을 텐데
There must be another way.
다른 방법이 있을 거야
시리우스
바틸다 백셧
마법의 역사
Harry? Hermione, where are you?
해리?
헤르미온느, 어디 있어?
I think I've found something.
와서 여길 봐
Lovely.
멋지네
"Regulus Arcturus Black."
"레귤러스 아르크투러스 블랙"
R.A.B.
"I know I will be dead
long before you read this.
"네가 이걸 읽을 때면
난 세상에 없겠지"
I have stolen the real Horcrux
and intend to destroy it."
"진짜 호크룩스를 훔쳤고
파괴할 거다"
R.A.B. is Sirius' brother.
R.A.B.가
시리우스 동생이었군
Yes.
그래
Question is, did he actually
destroy the real Horcrux?
진짜 호크룩스를
파괴했을까?
You've been spying
on us, have you?
우리를 훔쳐봤지?
Kreacher has been watching.
크리처는 계속
보고 있었어요
Maybe he knows where
the real locket is.
얘가 진짜 호크룩스
있는 곳을 알지 몰라
Have you ever seen this before?
이거 본 적 있어?
Kreacher?
크리처?
It's Master Regulus' locket.
레귤러스 주인님 거예요
But there were two,
weren't there?
원래 2개였지?
Where's the other one?
다른 하나는 어디 있어?
Kreacher doesn't know where
the other locket is.
크리처는 그게
어디 있는지 몰라요
Yes, but did you ever see it?
Was it in this house?
보긴 했어?
이 집 안에 있었어?
Filthy Mudblood.
천한 잡종!
- Death Eaters are coming...
- Ron.
- 죽음을 먹는 자들이…
- 론!
- Blood traitor, Weasley.
- Answer her.
- 동족의 배신자!
- 대답해
Yes.
네
It was here in this house.
이 집 안에 있었어요
A most evil object.
아주 사악한 물건이에요
How do you mean?
무슨 뜻이야?
Before Master Regulus died, he
ordered Kreacher to destroy it...
주인님이 죽으면서
파괴하라고 명했지만
but no matter how hard Kreacher
tried, he could not do it.
제가 아무리 애써도
소용없었어요
Well, where is it now?
지금은 어디 있지?
- Did someone take it?
- He came in the night.
- 누가 가져갔어?
- 그가 한밤중에 왔고
He took many things,
including the locket.
로켓뿐만 아니라
많은 걸 가져갔어요
Who did?
누가?
Who was it, Kreacher?
누구였어?
Mundungus.
먼던구스
Mundungus Fletcher.
먼던구스 플레처
Find him.
그를 찾아와
My father will hear about this.
우리 아버지한테 말할 거야
Hey, losers.
이봐, 찌질이들
He isn't here.
걔는 여기 없어
해리 포터
기피 대상자 1번
As your new Minister
for Magic...
신임 마법부 장관으로서
I promise to restore
this Temple of tolerance...
약속하건대
마법부의 영광을
to it's former glory.
되찾을 겁니다
마법은 힘이다
Therefore, beginning today...
오늘부터
each employee will
submit themselves...
마법부 모든 직원을
평가하여
for evaluation.
등급을 매기겠소
You have nothing to fear...
미리부터 겁먹을 거 없어요
if you have nothing to hide.
숨길 게 없다면…
- How much?
- Two Galleons.
Come on, time is money.
Cheers, pal.
- Snatchers!
- Move out of the way.
- I told you.
- Get out.
Squash him.
Be a bit gentler.
더 부드럽게
They have flesh memories.
스니치는 피부를 기억해
When Scrimgeour first gave it to you, I
thought it might open at your touch.
장관님이 줬을 때
네가 만지면 열릴 줄 알았어
That Dumbledore had hidden
something inside it.
덤블도어가
뭘 숨겼는지도 보고
Many of you are wondering...
why Voldemort has yet to show
himself now that he has vanquished...
the most powerful symbol of
opposition to him and his followers.
Get off.
놔!
Harry Potter, so long it's been.
해리 포터
참 오랜만이에요!
Get off me.
놓으라고!
As requested, Kreacher has
returned with the thief...
분부대로 크리처가
먼던구스를
- Expellliarmus...
- Mundungus Fletcher.
- 엑스펠리아르무스
- 잡아 왔어요
What you playing at? Setting a pair
of bleeding house-elves after me.
왜 집요정들한테
날 잡아 오라고 했어?
Dobby was only trying to help.
도비는 도왔을 뿐이에요
Dobby saw Kreacher in Diagon Alley,
which Dobby thought was curious.
도비가 다이애건 앨리에서
크리처를 봤는데
And then Dobby heard Kreacher
mention Harry Potter's name.
해리 포터 이름을
말하는 걸 들었어요
- I just...
- And then Dobby saw Kreacher...
그리곤 크리처가
- talking with the thief, Mundungus...
- I'm no thief.
- 도둑놈 먼던구스와…
- 난 도둑이 아니야!
You foul little... Git.
이 쬐깐한 괴물아
I'm a purveyor of rare
and wondrous objects.
희귀한 보물을 파는
장사꾼이지
You're a thief, Dung.
Everyone knows it.
도둑놈인 거 세상이 다 알죠
Master Weasley, so
good to see you again.
위즐리 님
다시 만나 반가워요
Wicked trainers.
신발 죽이네
Listen, I panicked
that night, all right?
그땐 무서워서 도망친 거야
Could I help it if Mad-Eye
fell off his broom?
매드아이 죽은 게
내 잘못은 아니잖아?
- You...
- Tell the truth.
사실대로 말해요
When you turned this place
over... Don't deny it.
이 집을 뒤졌을 때
You found a
locket, am I right?
로켓을 찾았죠?
Why? Was it valuable?
왜? 비싼 물건이야?
You still got it?
갖고 있어요?
No, he's worried he didn't
get enough money for it.
싸게 팔아서 후회되겠지
Bleeding give it away, didn't I?
거저 주다시피 뺏겼어
다이애건 앨리에서
장사하고 있었는데
There I was, flogging me
wares in Diagon Alley...
when some Ministry hag comes
up and asks to see me license.
마법부 할망구가 와선
허가증 보자면서
Says she's a mind to lock me up.
날 감옥 보내겠다고
으름장 놓잖아
And would've done it too, if she
hadn't taken a fancy to that locket.
그 로켓을 안 줬으면
진짜 그랬을 거야
- Who was she? The witch.
- Do you know? - No, I...
- 그게 누구였죠? 알아요?
- 아니
Well, she's there. Look.
사진 속에 있어, 봐
Bleeding bow and all.
옷깃 모양도 똑같아
마법부
호그와트 교육 개혁
Right, remember what we said.
좋아, 아까 말한 거 잊지 마
Don't speak to anyone unless
absolutely necessary.
꼭 필요한 경우 아니면
절대 말하지 말고
Just try and act normal. Do
what everybody else is doing.
자연스럽게 행동하고
남들이 하는 대로 해
If we do that, then with a bit
of luck, we'll get inside.
운이 좋아서 들어가면
- And then...
- It gets really tricky.
- 그다음엔…
- 복잡해지겠지
- Correct.
- Yeah.
맞아
- This is completely mental.
- Completely.
- 이건 미친 짓이야
- 완전히!
The world's mental.
세상이 미쳤잖아
Come on...
마시자
we've got a Horcrux to find.
로켓을 찾아야지
We flush ourselves in.
변기 통해서 들어가야 돼
That's bloody disgusting.
더러워 죽겠네
Name?
You. Come.
당신, 따라와
- What? What?
- Come on.
- 왜요?
- 어서
- What did I do?
- Just keep walking.
- 내가 뭘 어쨌게요?
- 잔말 마
- Are those...?
- Muggles.
- 밑에…
- 머글들이야
In their rightful place.
저게…
새 마법부의 시각이지
Gotta tell you, I'm starting
to freak out a bit.
솔직히, 난 좀 겁나
How long did you say this batch of
Polyjuice would last, Hermione?
폴리 주스 약효가
얼마나 간다고 했지?
I didn't.
몰라
Cattermole.
캐터몰
It's still raining inside my
office. That's two days now.
내 사무실 천장에서
이틀째 물이 새
Have you tried an umbrella?
그럼 우산 쓰세요
You do realize I'm going
downstairs, don't you, Cattermole?
내가 아래층에
가는 거 알지?
- Downstairs?
- To interrogate your wife.
- 아래층?
- 자네 아내 조사하러
Now, if my wife's blood
status were in doubt...
아내의 혈통이
의심받는 상황에서
and the head of the Department
of Magical Law Enforcement...
법률 강제 집행부 책임자가
일 시키면
needed a job doing, I think I
might just make that a priority.
재까닥 해야 되지 않겠어?
You have one hour.
1시간 주지
Oh, my God. What am I gonna do?
My wife's all alone downstairs.
맙소사, 어떡하지?
아내가 아래층에 있어!
- Ron, you don't have a wife.
- Oh, right.
- 론, 넌 아내 없거든?
- 참, 그렇지
Level 2.
But how do I stop it raining?
물 새는 걸 어떻게 막지?
Try "Finite Incantatem."
피니트 인칸타템
주문을 써 봐
Department of Magical
Law Enforcement...
마법사 법률
강제 집행부입니다
and Improper Use
of Magic Department.
This is you, Ron.
넌 여기서 내려
Finite Incantatem. Okay. And
if that doesn't work...?
피니트 인칸타템, 알았어
그게 안 먹히면…
Level 1, Minister of
Magic and support staff.
If we don't locate Umbridge
within the hour...
1시간 안에
엄브릿지 못 찾으면
we go find Ron and
come back another day.
론 데리고 그냥 나가자
- Deal?
- Yes.
- 알았지?
- 응
Ah, Mafalda. Travers
sent you, did he?
마팔다, 날 찾으러 왔어?
Good, we'll go straight down.
좋아, 바로 내려가자고
Albert, aren't you getting out?
알버트, 안 내려?
잡종들이 순수 혈통 사회에
가하는 위협
Runcorn.
알버트
돌로레스 엄브릿지
마법부 차관
머글 태생 등록
위원회 의장
Accio locket.
아씨오 로켓
잡종 퇴치법
추적 - 요주의 인물
All right, all right. Let's
calm down, shall we?
모두 진정해요
Let's get back to work, please.
일들 계속해요
Calm down.
진정해요
Runcorn.
알버트
Morning.
굿모닝
Ron, it's me.
론, 나야
Harry. Blimey, forgot
what you looked like.
해리, 변장 모습을
까먹었었어
Where's Hermione?
헤르미온느는?
She's gone down to the
courtrooms, with Umbridge.
엄브릿지랑
법정에 내려갔어
Bloody cold down here.
무지 춥네
I'm a half-blood. My
father was a wizard.
난 혼혈이에요
아버지가 마법사죠
William Alderton. He
worked here for 30 years.
여기서 30년을 일하셨어요
Perhaps you know him. Always
wore his jacket inside out.
항상 재킷을
뒤집어 입으셨고요
No, there's been a mistake.
I'm half-blood, you see.
착오가 틀림없어요
We must go back. I'm half-blood.
보내 줘요, 난 혼혈이라고요
- Mary Elizabeth Cattermole?
- Yes.
- 메리 캐터몰?
- 네
Of 27 Chislehurst Gardens,
Great Tolling, Evesham?
사는 곳은 이브셤
치즐허스트 가든 27번지?
- Yes.
- It's here.
- 네
- 여기 있어
Mother to Maisie, Ellie and
Alfred? Wife to Reginald?
세 아이의 어머니이자
레지널드의 아내?
Reg?
레지?
Thank you, Albert.
고마워, 알버트
Mary Elizabeth Cattermole?
메리 캐터몰?
Yes.
네
A wand was taken from you upon your
arrival at the Ministry today.
마법부에 도착했을 때
지팡이를 압수당했는데
Is this that wand?
이게 그 지팡이지?
Would you please tell the court from which
witch or wizard you took this wand?
어느 마법사한테
훔쳤는지 실토해
I didn't take it.
안 훔쳤어요
I got it in Diagon Alley, at
Ollivander's, when I was 11.
11살 때
올리밴더 가게에서 샀어요
It chose me.
그 지팡이가 절 선택했죠
You're lying.
거짓말 마
Wands only choose witches,
and you are not a witch.
지팡이는 마녀만 선택하는데
당신은 마녀가 아니잖아
But I am.
전 마녀예요
Tell them, Reg. Tell
them what I am.
여보, 내가 마녀라고 말해 줘
Reg, tell them what I am.
어서, 여보
What on earth are
you doing, Albert?
뭐하는 거야, 알버트?
You're lying, Dolores.
거짓말이잖아요, 돌로레스
And one mustn't tell lies.
거짓말하면 못쓰죠
Stupefy!
스투페파이
It's Harry Potter.
해리 포터야
It is, isn't it? This'll
be one to tell the kids.
그러네?
애들한테 꼭 말해 줘
Expecto Patronum!
익스펙토 패트로눔
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Mary, go home.
메리, 집에 가서
Get the kids.
애들 준비시켜
I'll meet you there. We have to get
out of the country, understand?
집에서 만나
이 나라를 떠날 거야
Mary, do as I say.
내 말대로 해
Mary?
메리?
Who's that?
누구야?
Long story. Nice meeting you.
얘기하자면 길어요
만나서 반가웠어요
It's Harry Potter.
해리 포터다
It's Harry. Harry Potter.
해리야, 해리 포터!
- There he is.
- Get him!
놈을 잡아!
- Stop him!
- 빨리!
- 잡아!
- Watch out.
- Look out.
This way!
Expellliarmus!
엑스펠리아르무스
Oh, my God.
Shh, shh, shh. It's all right.
It's okay.
괜찮을 거야
Harry. Harry,
quickly, in my bag.
해리! 내 가방 안을 봐
There's a bottle labeled
"Essence of Dittany."
디터니 원액이 든 병이 있어
Shh. Shh.
Okay, okay. Quickly.
괜찮아, 괜찮아
빨리!
- Accio Dittany.
- Shh.
아씨오 디터니
It's all right. Unstopper it.
괜찮아
마개를 따
Hermione, his arm.
론 팔이…
I know, just do it.
알아, 빨리!
It's okay.
괜찮아
- Okay, it's gonna sting a little bit.
- What happened? I thought we meant...
- 조금 따가울 거야
- 그리몰드 광장으로
- to be going back to Grimmauld Place.
- We were. We were. Shh.
- 가기로 했었잖아?
- 그랬지
It's all right. One
more, one more.
괜찮아, 한 번 더
We were there, we were there, but
Yaxley had hold of me, and I...
죽음을 먹는 자가
날 잡고 따라와서
I knew once he'd seen where
we were, we couldn't stay...
거기 있을 수 없었어
so I brought us here...
그래서 여기로 왔는데
but Ron got splinched.
론이 다쳤어
It's all right.
괜찮아
Protego Totalum.
프로테고 토탈룸
Salvio Hexia.
살비오 헥시아
What are you doing?
뭐해?
Protective enchantments.
방어 마법 치는 거야
I don't fancy another visit like the one
we had in Shaftesbury Avenue, do you?
또 죽음을 먹는 자들
공격을 받긴 싫으니까
You can get going on the tent.
넌 텐트를 쳐
- Tent?
- Protego Totalum.
- 텐트?
- 프로테고 토탈룸
Where am I supposed
to find a tent?
텐트를 어디서 구해?
Repello Muggletum. Muffliato.
레펠로 머글레툼
머플리아토
You first.
먼저 해
Dissendium.
디센디움
Incendio.
인센디오
Expulso.
엑스펄소
Diffindo.
디핀도
Reducto.
리덕토
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
We have to keep it safe until
we find out how to destroy it.
파괴할 때까진
안전하게 보관해야 돼
Seems strange, mate.
Dumbledore sends you off...
이해가 안 돼
덤블도어가
to find all these Horcruxes, but
doesn't tell you how to destroy them.
호크룩스 찾으래 놓고
파괴하는 법은 안 가르쳐 줬어
Doesn't that bother you?
이상하지 않아?
A goblin by the name
of Gornuk was killed.
고르눅이란 도깨비도
죽었습니다
It is believed that Muggle-born
Dean Thomas and a second goblin...
머글 태생인 딘 토마스는
both believed to have been
traveling with Tonks, Cresswell...
통스, 크레스웰
고르눅과 있었는데…
and Gornuk, may
have escaped.
If Dean is listening or anyone has
any knowledge of his whereabouts...
his parents and sisters
are desperate for news.
Meanwhile, a Muggle family of five
has been found dead in their home.
You know the spell, Harry.
주문을 알잖아, 해리
Tell me.
말해
Tell me, Gregorovitch.
지팡이 있는 곳 말해
그레고로비치
It was stolen from me.
누가 훔쳐 갔어요
Who was he? The thief?
누구지? 그 도둑놈이?
It was a boy. It was
he who took it.
어떤 꼬마가 가져갔어요
I never saw it again.
그 후론 못 봤어요
I swear on my life.
목숨을 걸고 맹세해요
I believe you.
믿어 주마
Avada Kedavra!
아바다 케다브라
I thought it had stopped.
이제 그만해
You can't keep letting
him in, Harry.
'그'의 머릿속을
들여다보지 마
You-Know-Who has
found Gregorovitch.
그레고로비치를
'그'가 찾아냈어
The wandmaker?
지팡이 제작자?
He wants something that
Gregorovitch used to have...
응, 그가 가졌던
지팡이를 찾고 있어
but I don't know what.
어떤 건진 모르지만
But he wants it desperately. I mean,
it's as if his life depends on it.
절박하게 찾고 있어
마치 자기 목숨이 걸린 것처럼
Don't.
놔둬
- It comforts him.
- It sets my teeth on edge.
- 론한테는 위로가 돼
- 난 화가 나
What's he expecting
to hear, good news?
좋은 뉴스라도
나오길 바라나?
- Who long expected it, the fall
of the Ministry was shocking.
I think he just hopes he
doesn't hear bad news.
나쁜 뉴스가 안 나오길
바라는 거지
We promise to remain
your eyes and ears-
How long before he can travel?
언제 떠날 수 있어?
- Bringing you news when we
can, from wherever we can.
I'm doing everything I can.
최선을 다하고 있어
You're not doing enough!
충분치 않아!
Take it off.
그거 빼
I said, take it off now.
목에서 빼라고
- Better?
- Loads.
- 낫지?
- 훨씬
We'll take it in turns, okay?
교대로 차자
Finch does admit his invention
currently has one short.
And now, other news:
Severus Snape, newly-appointed
headmaster of Hogwarts...
호그와트 신임 교장인
세베루스 스네이프는
has decreed that all students must
conform to the latest house rules.
학생들에게 새 교칙 준수를
당부했습니다
Hogwarts bears little resemblance to the
school under Dumbledore's leadership.
호그와트 마법 학교가
완전히 달라졌습니다
Snape's curriculum is severe, reflecting
the wishes of the Dark Lord...
어둠의 마왕의 뜻에 따라
수업이 이뤄지고
and infractions are dealt with harshly
by the two Death Eaters on staff.
죽음을 먹는 자들이
학생들을 통제합니다
What's that?
뭐지?
What's that smell?
무슨 냄새야?
- What you doing?
- It's heavy.
- 왜?
- 무거워서
Oh, sorry. Do you
want me to carry it?
내가 대신 들까?
- Yeah, thank you. - Don't
be ridiculous. Pick it up.
- 그럼 고맙지
- 웃기지 말고 들어
Numpty.
등신
Snatchers.
머글 사냥꾼들이야
Good to know your
enchantments work.
방어 마법 쳐 놓길 잘했네
He could smell it. My perfume.
향수 냄새는 숨기지 못했어
I've told you...
순간 이동하기엔
Ron isn't strong
enough to Apparate.
론이 너무 약한 상태야
Well, then, we'll go on foot.
그럼 걸어서 가자
And next time, Hermione, as much as I
like your perfume, just don't wear any.
향수 냄새가 좋긴 한데
이젠 뿌리지 마
And now for the names of
missing witches and wizards.
실종된 마법사 명단입니다
These are confirmed.
다행히 오늘은
Thankfully, the list
is short today.
그리 많지 않군요
Jason and Alison Denbright.
제이슨과
앨리슨 덴브라이트
Oh. Thank you.
고마워
Bella, Jake, Charlie,
and Madge Farley.
벨라, 제이크, 찰리
매지 팔리
Joe Laurie.
조 로리
Eleanor Sarah Gibbs.
엘리노어 새라 깁스
Harry and Bronwyn Trigg.
해리와 브론윈 트리그
Rob and Ellie Dowson.
Georgia Clark-Day.
Joshua Flexson.
George Coutas.
Gabriella and Emily Mather.
Jacob and Mimi Erland.
William and Brian Gallagher.
He doesn't know what
he's doing, does he?
해리한테 계획 없지?
None of us do.
우리도 없잖아
Toby and Olivia Gleaves.
Katie and James Killick.
Elsie Valentine Schroeder.
Jennifer Winston.
Tamsin and Lola Hillicker.
Scarlet and Kitty Sharp.
Oh, my God.
맙소사!
What?
왜?
I'll tell you in a minute.
금방 말해 줄게
Maybe you could tell me now.
그냥 지금 말해
The sword of Gryffindor,
it's goblin-made.
그리핀도르의 칼은
도깨비가 만든 거야
Brilliant.
멋지네
No, you don't understand.
아직 이해 못 했구나
Dirt and rust have no
effect on the blade.
그 칼은 녹슬거나
먼지도 끼지 않아
It only takes in that
which makes it stronger.
자기를 강하게 하는 것만
흡수하지
Okay.
그래서?
Harry, you've already
destroyed one Horcrux, right?
호크룩스 하나를
파괴했었잖아
Tom Riddle's diary in
the Chamber of Secrets.
비밀의 방에서
톰 리들의 일기장
With a Basilisk fang. If you tell
me you've got one of those...
바실리스크의 송곳니로
파괴했지, 네 가방 속에
- in that bloody beaded bag of yours...
- Don't you see?
- 그런 게 들었다면…
- 모르겠어?
In the Chamber of Secrets, you stabbed the
Basilisk with the sword of Gryffindor.
바실리스크를 찌른 건
그리핀도르의 칼이야
It's blade is impregnated
with Basilisk venom.
칼날에 그 뱀의 독이
스며들었을 거야
It only takes in that
which makes it stronger.
강하게 하는 것만 흡수한다
- Exactly, which is why...
- It can destroy Horcruxes.
- 맞아, 그러니까…
- 그 칼로 호크룩스를 깰 수 있어
That's why Dumbledore left
it to you in his will.
그래서 덤블도어가
네게 준 거야
You are brilliant, Hermione.
Truly.
넌 진짜 천재야, 헤르미온느
Actually, I'm highly logical, which allows
me to look past extraneous detail...
난 꽤 논리적이라
남들이 놓치는 사소한 것들에서
and perceive clearly
that which others overlook.
중요한 힌트를 얻어
Yeah, there's only one
problem, of course.
근데 문제가 하나 있잖아
The sword was stolen.
칼을 도난당했지
Yeah, I'm still here.
그래, 나 아직 여기 있어
But you two carry on. Don't
let me spoil the fun.
계속해
재미 망치긴 싫거든
- What's wrong?
- Wrong? Nothing's wrong.
- 문제 있어?
- 문제? 그런 거 없어
Not according to you, anyway.
네 말대로라면…
Look, if you've got something to
say, don't be shy. Spit it out.
할 말 있으면
둘러대지 말고 해
All right, I'll spit it out. But
don't expect me to be grateful...
좋아, 할게
찾을 게 하나 늘었다고
because there's another
damn thing we've gotta find.
고마워할 거란 기대 마
I thought you knew what
you signed up for.
힘들 거라는 거 알았잖아
Yeah. I thought I did too.
안다고 생각했지
Well then, I'm sorry, but
I don't quite understand.
미안하지만 난 이해가 안 돼
What part of this isn't living
up to your expectations?
도대체
뭐가 그렇게 불만이야?
Did you think we were gonna
be staying in a hotel?
고급 호텔에서 지내며
Finding a Horcrux every other day?
Thought you'd be back by Christmas?
호크룩스를 금방 다 찾고
성탄절까진 돌아갈 줄 알았어?
I just thought, after
all this time...
해낸 게 아무것도 없잖아
we would've achieved something. I
thought you knew what you were doing.
덤블도어가
네게 쓸 만한 정보를
I thought Dumbledore told
you something worthwhile.
- I thought you had a plan. - I told
you everything Dumbledore told me.
- 줬는지 알았어
- 교수님께 들은 건 다 말해 줬잖아
In case you haven't noticed,
we found a Horcrux.
호크룩스 하나는
벌써 찾았고
Yeah, and we're as close to getting rid of
it as we are to finding the rest of them.
찾은 건 파괴 못 했고
나머지는 못 찾았지
Ron. Please, take...
론, 그거 빼
Take the Horcrux off. You
wouldn't be saying this...
호크룩스 빼
그걸 차고 있어서
if you hadn't been
wearing it all day.
- 이러는 거야
- 왜 밤마다 라디오 듣는 줄 알아?
Want to know why I
listen to that radio?
To make sure I don't hear Ginny's
name, or Fred, or George or Mom.
우리 가족이 무사한지
확인하고 싶어서야
You think I'm not listening? You
think I don't know how this feels?!
난 안 듣는 줄 알아?
네 기분 모를까 봐?
No, you don't know how it feels!
넌 몰라
Your parents are dead.
You have no family.
부모 없는 고아가
걱정할 게 있겠어?
- Stop. Stop.
- Fine, then go!
- 그만해!
- 그럼 가!
Go, then!
가라고!
Fine.
Ron.
론
And you?
넌?
Are you coming or you staying?
갈 거야, 남을 거야?
Fine. I get it.
좋아, 알았다고
I saw you two the other night.
요 전날 밤 너희들을 봤어
Ron, that's... That's nothing.
그건 오해야
Ron...
론!
Ron, where are you going?
어디 가?
Please, come back.
제발 돌아와
Ron.
론!
Ron!
Salvio Hexia.
살비오 헥시아
Repellum Muggletum.
레펠룸 머글레툼
Salvio Hexia.
살비오 헥시아
Poor old Jim's
white as a ghost.
He's found the
answer that we lost.
We're all weeping now
Weeping because.
There ain't nothing we
can do To protect you.
O children.
Lift up your voice.
Children.
Rejoice, rejoice.
Hey, little train,
we're jumping on.
The train that goes
to the kingdom.
We're happy, Ma
We're having fun.
And the train ain't
even left the station.
Hey, little train,
wait for me.
I once was blind
but now I see.
Have you left a seat for me?
Is that such a stretch
of the imagination?
Hey, little train,
wait for me.
I was held in chains
but now I'm free.
I'm hanging in there
Don't you see?
In this process
of elimination.
Hey, little train,
we're jumping on.
The train that goes
to the kingdom.
We're happy, Ma
We're having fun.
It's beyond my
wildest expectation.
Hey, little train,
we're jumping on.
The train that goes
to the kingdom.
We're happy, Ma
We're having fun.
The train ain't even
left the station
나는 끝에서 열린다
Hermione.
헤르미온느?
Hermione? You were right.
네가 옳았어
Snitches have flesh memories...
스니치는 피부를 기억하지?
but I didn't catch the first Snitch
with my hand, I almost swallowed it.
처음에 손으로 잡지 않았었어
입으로 물었지
- "I open at the close."
- What do you think that means?
- "나는 끝에서 열린다"
- 무슨 뜻일까?
I don't know.
모르겠어
I found something as well.
나도 찾은 게 있어
At first I thought it was an eye,
but now I don't think it is.
눈인 줄 알았는데
그게 아니야
It isn't a rune, and it isn't
anywhere in Spellman's Syllabary.
룬 문자도 아니고
주술사 문자표에도 없어
Somebody inked it in. It isn't part
of the book. Somebody Drew it.
책의 일부가 아니라
누군가가 그려 넣었어
Luna's dad was wearing that
at Bill and Fleur's wedding.
루나 아빠가
그런 상징을 차고 있었어
Why would someone draw
it in a children's book?
왜 그걸 동화책에
그려 놨을까?
Look, Hermione,
I've been thinking.
생각해 봤는데
I want to go to Godric's Hollow.
고드릭 골짜기에 가고 싶어
It's where I was born. It's
where my parents died.
내가 태어나고
부모님이 돌아가신 곳
That's exactly where he'll expect you to
go because it means something to you.
'그'도 네가
거기 오길 예상할 거야
Yeah, but it means something
to him too, Hermione.
'그'한테도
의미 있는 곳이야
You-Know-Who almost died there.
거기서 죽을 뻔했으니까
I mean, isn't that exactly the type of
place he'd be likely to hide a Horcrux?
그런 곳에 호크룩스를
숨기지 않겠어?
It's dangerous, Harry.
너무 위험한데…
But even I have to admit, recently I've
been thinking we'll have to go there.
실은, 나도
같은 생각을 했어
I think it's possible something
else is hidden there.
다른 게
숨겨져 있을지 몰라
What?
어떤 거?
The sword.
그 칼
If Dumbledore wanted you to find it, but
didn't want it in the Ministry's hands...
덤블도어가 칼을 숨기기엔
최적의 장소지
where better to hide it than the
birthplace of the founder of Gryffindor?
그리핀도르가
태어난 곳이니까
Hermione...
헤르미온느
Don't ever let me give
you a haircut again.
다시는 머리 잘라 달라고
하지 마
I still think we should've
used Polyjuice Potion.
폴리 주스를 쓸 걸 그랬어
No.
아니
This is where I was born.
내가 태어난 곳이야
I'm not returning
as someone else.
다른 사람 모습은 싫어
Good night. Ha-ha-ha.
굿나잇!
Harry, I think it's
Christmas Eve.
크리스마스 이브인가 봐
Listen.
들어 봐
Do you think they'd be
in there, Hermione?
저기 계실까?
My mom and dad.
우리 부모님?
Yeah, I think they would.
그럴 거 같아
"Ignotus Peverell."
"이그노투스 피브렐"
Hey, Harry?
해리?
제임스와 릴리 포터를
기억하며
Merry Christmas, Hermione.
메리 크리스마스
Merry Christmas, Harry.
Harry, there's someone
watching us. By the church.
누가 우리를 보고 있어
교회 옆에서…
I think I know who that is.
누군지 알겠어
I don't like this, Harry.
예감이 안 좋아
Hermione, she knew Dumbledore.
She might have the sword.
덤블도어와 알던 분이야
그 칼을 가지고 있을지 몰라
This is where they
died, Hermione.
여기서 돌아가셨어
This is where he murdered them.
여기서 '그'가
부모님을 죽였어
You're Bathilda, aren't you?
바틸다 백셧, 맞죠?
Here, let me do that.
제가 할게요
Miss Bagshot, who is this man?
백셧 부인
이 남자는 누구죠?
Harry.
해리
Lumos.
루모스
덤블도어의 삶과 거짓말
Harry!
해리!
Confringo!
콘프링고
Are you feeling better?
좀 괜찮아?
You've outdone yourself
this time, Hermione.
이번에는 장소를
제대로 골랐네
The Forest of Dean.
딘의 숲이야
I came here once with
Mom and Dad, years ago.
몇 년 전에 부모님과 왔었어
It's just how I remember it.
내 기억 그대로야
The trees, the
river, everything.
나무, 강…
전부 다
Like nothing's changed.
하나도 안 변한 것처럼
Not true, of course.
Everything's changed.
물론 다 변했겠지만
If I brought my parents back here now, they
probably wouldn't recognize any of it.
지금 부모님을 모셔와도
못 알아보실 거야
Not the trees, not the river...
나무도, 강도
not even me.
심지어 나도…
Maybe we should just
stay here, Harry.
그냥 여기서 살면 어떨까?
Grow old.
늙어 가면서…
You wanted to know who the
boy in the photograph was.
사진 속 남자가
누구냐고 물었지?
I know.
내가 알아냈어
Gellert Grindelwald.
겔러트 그린델왈드
He's the thief I saw in
Gregorovitch's Wand Shop.
지팡이 가게에서 본
도둑이야
Speaking of which,
where is my wand?
그건 그렇고
내 지팡이 어디 있어?
Where's my wand, Hermione?
As we were leaving Godric's Hollow,
I cast a curse and it rebounded.
도망치면서
주문을 걸었는데 부러졌어
I'm sorry.
미안해
- I tried to mend it, but wands
are different. - It's done.
- 고치려고 해봤는데…
- 됐어
Leave me yours. Go
inside and get warm.
네 지팡이를 줘
들어가서 몸 녹여
I'll take the locket as well.
로켓도 주고
Trust me.
날 믿으렴
Lumos.
루모스
Accio sword.
아씨오 칼
Diffindo.
디핀도
- Hermione?
- Are you mental?
- 헤르미온느?
- 돌았냐?
It was you?
너였어?
Well, yeah. Bit
obvious, I think.
그래, 여기 너 말고
나밖에 더 있나?
And you cast the Doe
as well, did you?
네가 암사슴 보냈어?
- No, I thought that was you.
- No, my Patronus is a stag.
- 너 아니었어?
- 내 패트로누스는 수사슴이야
Right. Yeah. Antlers.
참, 그렇지
뿔이 달렸으니까
Okay, Ron. Do it.
좋아, 론
파괴해
I can't handle it. That thing affects me
more than it affects you and Hermione.
난 못해, 너희보다는 내가
감당 못 하잖아
- All the more reason.
- No. I can't.
- 그럴수록 네가 해야지
- 난 못해
Then why are you here?
그럼 왜 왔어?
Why did you come back?
왜 돌아온 거야?
Now, I'll have to speak to it in order for
it to open. When it does, don't hesitate.
내가 말을 하면 열릴 거야
그럼 주저하지 마
I don't know what's in there,
but it'll put up a fight.
호락호락하진 않을 거야
The bit of Riddle that was in
that diary tried to kill me.
톰 리들 일기장도
날 죽이려고 했었어
All right.
하나
One...
two...
둘
three.
셋
I have seen your
heart, and it is mine.
난 네 마음속을 보았다
그러므로 넌 내 것이다
I have seen your dreams,
Ronald Weasley...
난 네 꿈을 보았다
론 위즐리
and I have seen your fears.
그리고 네 두려움도 보았다
Least loved by your Mother,
who craved a daughter.
딸을 편애한 엄마한테
가장 사랑을 못 받았지
Least loved by the girl
who prefers your friend.
네 친구를 더 좋아하는
여자 친구 사랑도 못 받고
Ron, kill it!
론, 파괴해!
We were better without you.
네가 없을 때가
훨씬 더 좋았어
Happier without you.
더 행복했다고
Who could look at you
compared to Harry Potter?
누가 해리를 두고
널 봐주겠어?
What are you compared
with the Chosen One?
걔는 선택받았고
넌 아무것도 아니야
Ron, it's lying!
거짓말이야!
Your Mother confessed she would
have preferred me as a son.
너희 엄마는
내가 아들이었음 좋겠대
What woman would take you?
어떤 여자가
널 좋아하겠어?
You are nothing.
넌 아무것도 아니야
Nothing.
아무것도…
Nothing compared to him.
해리에 비하면
아무것도 아니야
Just think...
이제…
only three to go.
3개만 더 파괴하면 되네
Hermione?
헤르미온느?
Is everything all right?
괜찮은 거야?
It's fine. Actually, you
know, it's more than fine.
그래, 괜찮은 거 이상이지
Hey.
안녕
You complete ass,
Ronald Weasley!
론 위즐리, 이 나쁜 놈!
You show up here after
weeks, and you say "hey"?
몇 주 만에 나타나선
기껏 하는 소리가 "안녕"?
- Where's my wand? Where's my wand?
- I don't know.
- 내 지팡이 어디 있어?
- 몰라
- Harry Potter, give me my wand.
- I don't have it.
- 내 지팡이 내놔!
- 나한테 없어
- How come he's got your wand?
- Never mind why he's got my wand.
- 왜 해리가 가졌어?
- 넌 알 거 없어!
What is that?
그건 뭐야?
You destroyed it.
파괴했구나
And how is it that you just happen
to have the sword of Gryffindor?
그리핀도르의 칼을
왜 네가 갖고 있어?
It's a long story.
얘기하자면 길어
- Don't think this changes anything.
- Oh, of course not.
화 풀렸다고 착각하지 마
기껏 호크룩스 하나 부쉈는데
화가 풀리겠어?
I only just destroyed a bloody Horcrux.
Why would that change anything?
Look, I wanted to come
back as soon as I left.
떠나자마자
돌아오고 싶었지만
- I just didn't know how to find you.
- Yeah, how did you find us?
- 너희를 찾을 수가 없었어
- 어떻게 찾았어?
With this. It doesn't
just turn off lights.
이걸로
그냥 불빛만 끄는 게 아니야
I don't know how it works, but Christmas
morning I was sleeping in this little pub...
크리스마스 아침에
머글 사냥꾼 피해서
keeping away from
some Snatchers...
술집에서 자고 있는데
and I heard it.
그때 들렸어
It?
뭐가?
A voice...
목소리
your voice, Hermione...
네 목소리, 헤르미온느
coming out of it.
딜루미네이터에서…
- And what exactly did I say, may I ask?
- My name.
- 내가 뭐랬는데?
- 내 이름
Just my name.
내 이름을 불렀어
Like a whisper.
속삭이듯이
So I took it, clicked it, and
this tiny ball of light appeared.
그래서 이걸 켰더니
빛이 나타났어
And I knew.
단번에 알았지
And sure enough, it floated
toward me, the ball of light...
그리곤 그 빛이
날 향해 흘러오더니
went right to my chest,
straight through me. Right here.
내 가슴속으로 들어가더라
여기로
And I knew it was gonna take me where
I needed to go, so I Disapparated...
그래서 그걸 믿고
순간 이동을 했는데
and came to this hillside.
어떤 언덕이었어
It was dark. I had
no idea where I was.
캄캄했고 어딘지 모르겠고
I just hoped that one of
you would show yourself.
그저 너희가 있길 바랐는데
And you did.
진짜 있었어
I've always liked these
flames Hermione makes.
난 헤르미온느가 만드는
불빛이 좋아
How long do you reckon
she'll stay mad at me?
언제쯤 화가 풀릴까?
Well, just keep talking about that little
ball of light touching your heart...
가슴속으로 들어간
그 빛 얘기를 계속해 줘
and she'll come round.
그럼 풀릴 거야
It was true. Every word.
보탠 거 하나 없이
다 진짜야
This is gonna sound crazy...
미친 소리 같지만
but I think that's why Dumbledore
left it to me, the Deluminator.
그래서 덤블도어가
딜루미네이터를 준 거 같아
I think he knew that somehow I'd need it
to find my way back, and she'd lead me.
이런 일이 생길 걸
알고 있었던 거지
Bloody hell, I just realized,
you need a wand, don't you?
참, 지팡이 필요하지?
- Yeah.
- I've got one here.
- 응
- 나한테 있어
It's a blackthorn. Ten inches.
블랙손 나무로 만든 거야
Nothing special, but
I reckon it'll do.
특별한 건 없지만
쓸 만할 거야
Took if off a Snatcher
a couple of weeks ago.
얼마 전
머글 사냥꾼한테서 훔쳤어
Don't tell Hermione this, but
they're a bit dim, Snatchers.
그자들은 멍청해
한참 모자라지
This one was definitely part
troll, the smell of him.
몸 냄새도 고약하고
Engorgio.
잉고르지오
- Reducio!
- What's going on in there?
- 리듀시오
- 둘이 뭐해?
- Nothing.
- 아무것도!
We need to talk.
얘기 좀 해
Yeah, all right.
좋아
- I want to go see Xenophilius Lovegood.
- Sorry?
- 루나 아빠를 만나러 가자
- 뭐?
See this?
이건
It's a letter Dumbledore wrote to
Grindelwald. Look at the signature.
덤블도어가 그린델왈드한테
보냈던 편지야, 서명을 봐
It's the Mark again.
그 상징이야
It keeps cropping up.
계속 나타나
In Beedle the Bard, in the
graveyard in Godric's Hollow.
'방랑시인 비들 이야기' 책
고드릭 골짜기 묘지에서도
It was there too.
딴 곳에도 있었어
- Where? - Outside
Gregorovitch's Wand Shop.
- 어디?
- 그레고로비치 지팡이 가게 밖에
But what does it mean?
뭘 뜻하는데?
Look, you've got no idea where the
next Horcrux is, and neither do I...
다음 호크룩스가
어디 있는지 모르잖아
but this, this
means something.
이게 단서일 거야
- I'm sure of it.
- Yeah. Hermione's right.
- 틀림없어
- 헤르미온느가 옳아
We ought to see Lovegood.
만나러 가자
Let's vote on it.
Those in favor?
투표로 정할까?
찬성하는 사람?
You're not still mad
at him, are you?
아직도 론한테
화난 거 아니지?
I'm always mad at him.
걔한테는 늘 화나
Luna.
루나
- 루나
날아다니는 자두에
접근하지 마시오
'이러쿵 저러쿵' 편집자
X. 러브굿
"Keep off the dirigible plums."
"날아다니는 자두에
접근하지 마시오"
What is it? Who are you?
뭐냐? 너희들 누구야?
What do you want?
뭘 원해?
Hello, Mr. Lovegood. I'm Harry
Potter. We met a few months ago.
안녕하세요, 해리 포터예요
결혼식에서 만났죠
Could we come in?
들어가도 돼요?
- Where is Luna?
- Luna?
- 루나는 어디 있죠?
- 루나?
She'll be along.
금방 올 거야
So how can I help
you, Mr. Potter?
무슨 일로 왔지, 포터 군?
Well, actually...
결혼식장에서
It was about something you were wearing
round your neck at the wedding. A symbol.
아저씨가 목에 걸고 있던
상징 때문에요
You mean this?
이거?
Yes.
네
That exactly.
이거요
What we've wondered
is, what is it?
저희가 궁금한 건…
대체 뭐죠?
What is it?
몰라서 물어?
Well, it's the sign of the
Deathly Hallows, of course.
죽음의 성물 상징이잖아
- The what?
- 네?
The Deathly Hallows.
죽음의 성물
I assume you're all familiar with
"The Tale of the Three Brothers."
'삼형제 이야기' 들어 봤지?
- Yes.
- No.
- 네
- 아니요
I have it in here.
제게 책이 있어요
"There were once
three brothers...
"삼형제가 해질녘에"
who were traveling along a
lonely, winding road at twilight."
"으슥한 꼬부랑길을
걸어가고 있었어요"
Midnight. Mom always
said "midnight."
우리 엄마는 자정이랬어
But "twilight's" fine.
Better, actually.
해질녘도 좋네
솔직히 훨씬 낫다
Do you want to read it?
네가 읽을래?
No. It's fine.
아냐
"There were once
three brothers..."
"삼형제가 해질녘에"
who were traveling along a
lonely, winding road at twilight.
"으슥한 꼬부랑길을
걸어가고 있었어요"
In time, the brothers reached a
river too treacherous to pass.
"물이 사납게 흐르는
강에 도착하자"
But being learned in
the magical arts...
"마법을 배운 삼형제는"
the three brothers simply waved
their wands and made a bridge.
"지팡이를 가볍게 흔들어
다리를 만들었죠"
Before they could
cross, however...
"다리를 건너려는데"
they found their path
blocked by a hooded figure.
"두건을 쓴 자가
길을 막았어요"
It was Death, and
he felt cheated.
"그는 죽음이었고
화가 나 있었죠"
Cheated because travelers would
normally drown in the river.
"다른 사람들처럼
빠져 죽지 않아서요"
But Death was cunning.
"영리한 죽음은"
He pretended to congratulate the
three brothers on their magic...
"삼형제의 마법을
칭찬하면서"
and said that each had earned a prize for
having been clever enough to evade him.
"자신을 피한 것에 대한
상을 주겠다고 했어요"
The oldest asked for a wand more
powerful than any in existence.
"첫째는 세상에서 제일 강력한
지팡이를 원했고"
So Death fashioned him one from
an elder tree that stood nearby.
"죽음은 딱총나무 가지로
지팡이를 만들어 줬어요"
The second brother decided he wanted
to humiliate Death even further...
"둘째는 죽음에게
더 굴욕감을 주기 위해"
and asked for the power to
recall loved ones from the grave.
"죽은 사람을 살릴 힘을
달라고 했죠"
So Death plucked a stone from the
river and offered it to him.
"죽음은 돌을 꺼내
그에게 주었어요"
Finally, Death turned
to the third brother.
"마지막으로 죽음은
셋째에게 물었죠"
A humble man...
"겸손한 셋째는"
he asked for something that would
allow him to go forth from that place...
"죽음을 피해
강을 건너게 해줄"
without being
followed by Death.
"물건을 달라고 했어요"
And so it was that Death reluctantly
handed over his own Cloak of Invisibility.
"죽음은 마지못해 자신의
투명 망토를 내주었어요"
The first brother traveled
to a distant village...
"첫째는 멀리 떨어진
마을에 가서"
where, with the
Elder Wand in hand...
"딱총나무 지팡이로"
he killed a wizard with
whom he had once quarreled.
"자신과 다투었던
마법사를 죽였고"
Drunk with the power that the
Elder Wand had given him...
"딱총나무 지팡이를 자랑하며"
he bragged of
his invincibility.
"천하무적이 됐노라
떠들어댔죠"
But that night, another
wizard stole the wand...
"하지만 그날 밤
다른 마법사가"
and slit the brother's
throat for good measure.
"지팡이를 훔치고
그의 목을 벴어요"
And so Death took the first
brother for his own.
"그리하여 죽음은
첫째를 차지했죠"
The second brother
journeyed to his home...
"집으로 간 둘째는"
where he took the stone and
turned it thrice in hand.
"손 안에서 돌을
세 번 굴렸어요"
To his delight, the girl he'd once hoped
to marry before her untimely death...
"그러자 너무도 사랑했던
죽었던 약혼녀가"
appeared before him.
"그의 앞에 나타났지만"
Yet, soon she turned sad and cold for
she did not belong in the mortal world.
"그녀는 슬프고 차가웠어요
인간 세계에 속하지 않았으니까요"
Driven mad with
hopeless longing...
"크게 상심한 둘째는"
the second brother killed
himself so as to join her.
"그녀를 위해
자기 목숨을 끊었고"
And so Death took
the second brother.
"그렇게 죽음은
둘째도 차지했어요"
As for the third brother...
"죽음은 오랫동안"
Death searched for many years
but was never able to find him.
"셋째를 찾았지만
찾을 수가 없었죠"
Only when he attained a great
age did the youngest brother...
"셋째는 죽을 때가 돼서야"
shed the Cloak of Invisibility
and give it to his son.
"투명 망토를 벗어
아들에게 주었고"
He then greeted Death as an old
friend and went with him gladly...
"죽음을 오랜 친구로
받아들여"
"...departing this
life as equals."
"동등한 존재로서
이 세상을 떠났어요"
So there you are. Those
are the Deathly Hallows.
바로 그거야
그것들이 죽음의 성물이지
I'm sorry, Sir. I still
don't quite understand.
죄송하지만 이해가 안 돼요
Where's that pen I had?
The Elder Wand.
딱총나무 지팡이
The most powerful
wand ever made.
세상에서
가장 강력한 지팡이
The Resurrection Stone.
부활의 돌
The Cloak of Invisibility.
투명 망토
Together, they make
the Deathly Hallows.
이것들을 합치면
죽음의 성물이 되고
Together, they make
one master of Death.
이것들을 가진 자는
죽음의 지배자가 돼
That Mark was on a grave
in Godric's Hollow.
고드릭 골짜기 무덤에
그 상징이 있었어요
Uh, Mr. Lovegood, does
the Peverell Family...
피브렐 가문이
have anything to do
with the Deathly Hallows?
그것과 관련 있나요?
Uh... Uh...
Ignotus... Excuse me... And his
brothers, Cadmus and Antioch...
이그노투스, 잠깐만…
그의 형제들이 처음
are thought to be the original
owners of the Hallows...
성물을 소유했고
and therefore the inspiration
for the story. Uh... Uh...
그 이야기의
모티브가 됐다고 해
But your tea's gone cold.
차가 식었네
I'll be right back.
금방 오마
Let's go down here.
Let's get out of here.
그냥 가자
I'm not drinking any more
of that stuff, hot or cold.
그 차는 더 못 마시겠어
Thank you, Sir.
감사합니다
- You forgot the water.
- Water?
- 물 데우는 걸 잊으셨어요
- 뭐?
For the tea.
차 끓일 물요
Did...? Did I?
그래?
How silly of me.
바보 같기는
It's no matter. We really
should be going anyway.
저희는 그만 갈게요
No, you can't!
안돼, 못 가!
Sir?
아저씨?
You're my only hope.
너희는 내 유일한 희망이야
They were angry, you see,
about what I'd been writing.
그들이 내 기사에 화가 나선
So they took her.
내 딸을 잡아갔어
They took my Luna.
루나를 잡아갔어
My Luna.
우리 루나를…
But it's really you they want.
하지만
그들이 원하는 건 너야
Who took her, Sir?
누가 잡아갔죠?
Voldemort.
볼드모트
Stop! I've got him!
그만해! 해리를 잡았어!
That treacherous little bleeder.
Is there no one we can trust?
세상에 믿을 마법사
아무도 없다니까!
They kidnapped her
because he supported me.
날 옹호해서
딸이 납치됐잖아
He was just desperate.
절박해서 그런 거야
I'll do the enchantments.
방어 마법 칠게
Hello, beautiful.
안녕, 이쁜이
Well, don't hang
about, snatch them.
뒷짐 지고 있을 거야?
잡아!
Harry.
해리
Tell me, Grindelwald.
Tell me where it is.
그린델왈드
어디 있는지 말해
Grindelwald. Grindelwald.
Grindelwald.
그린델왈드, 그린델왈드
Hello, Tom. I knew you
would come one day...
반가워, 톰
언젠간 올 줄 알았지
but surely you must know I
no longer have what you seek.
근데 그 지팡이는
이젠 나한테 없어
- Tell me, Grindelwald. Tell
me where it is. - Ha-ha-ha.
어디 있는지 말해
그린델왈드
Tell me who possesses it.
누가 가졌는지 말해
The Elder Wand lies
with him, of course...
딱총나무 지팡이는
그와 함께
buried in the earth.
땅속에 묻혀 있지
Dumbledore.
덤블도어
The Hallows exist...
'그'가 노리는 성물은
but he's only after one of them,
the last one. He knows where it is.
딱총나무 지팡이고
어디 있는지를 알아냈어
He's gonna have it by the end of the night.
You-Know-Who's found the Elder Wand.
오늘 밤에 손에 넣을 거야
- Don't touch her. Unh!
- Leave him.
- 걔한테 손대지 마!
- 해치지 마요!
Your boyfriend will get
worse than that...
네 남자 친구가
얌전히 안 굴면
Get off me.
If he doesn't learn
to behave himself.
이건 약과일 거야
What happened to you, ugly?
꼴이 왜 그래, 얼빵?
No, not you.
아니, 너 말고
- What's your name?
- Dudley. Vernon Dudley.
- 이름이 뭐냐?
- 두들리, 버논 두들리요
Check it.
확인해
And you, my lovely...
이쁜이, 넌?
what do they call you?
이름이 뭐야?
Penelope Clearwater, half-blood.
페네로프 클리어워터
혼혈이에요
There's no Vernon
Dudley on here.
버논 두들리는 명단에 없어
Did you hear that, ugly? The
list says you're lying.
들었어?
네가 거짓말을 한대
How come you don't want
us to know who you are?
왜 정체를 숨기려고 했지?
The list's wrong. I
told you who I am.
명단이 잘못된 거예요
Change of plan.
계획을 바꾼다
We're not taking this
lot to the Ministry.
얘들은 마법부로
안 데려간다
Get Draco.
드레이코를 데려와
Well?
어때?
- I can't be sure.
- Draco. Look closely, son.
- 잘 모르겠어요
- 드레이코, 자세히 봐
If we are the ones to hand
Potter over to the Dark Lord...
우리가 어둠의 마왕께
해리 포터를 넘기면
everything would be forgiven. All
would be as it was, you understand?
모든 걸 용서해 주실 거야
옛날로 돌아간다고, 알아들어?
Now, we won't be forgetting who actually
caught him, I hope, Mr. Malfoy.
아뇨, 놈들을 잡은 건
우리예요, 말포이 씨
You dare to talk to me
like that in my own house?
감히, 내 집에서?
말조심해!
Lucius.
루시우스
Don't be shy, sweetie.
Come over.
망설일 거 없어, 이리 와
Now, if this isn't who we think it is,
Draco, and we call him, he'll kill us all.
엉뚱한 애를 잡아 놓고
'그분'을 불렀다간 우린 다 죽어
We need to be absolutely sure.
확실해야 돼
What's wrong with his face?
- 얼굴이 왜 이렇죠?
- 그래, 왜 이래?
Yes, what is wrong
with his face?
He came to us like that.
처음부터 그랬어요
Something he picked up
in the Forest, I reckon.
병에 걸렸나 봐요
Or ran into a Stinging Jinx.
Was it you, dearie?
쏘기 주문에 걸렸거나…
네가 걸었니?
Give me her wand. We'll see
what her last spell was.
얘 지팡이를 줘
마지막 주문 알아보자고
Ah. Got you.
딱 걸렸어
What is that?
그건 뭐야?
Where'd you get that from?
어디서 났어?
It was in her bag when we searched
her. Reckon it's mine now.
가방 속에 있었죠
이젠 내 거예요
Are you mad?
미쳤어요?
Go! Get out!
나가!
Cissy, put the boys
in the cellar.
씨시
녀석들을 지하에 가둬!
I want to have a little conversation
with this one, girl-to-girl.
얘랑 단둘이 얘기 좀 해야겠어
여자 대 여자로!
What are we gonna do? We can't
leave Hermione alone with her.
헤르미온느를
그 여자랑 두면 안 돼
Ron?
론?
Harry?
해리?
Luna?
루나?
That sword is meant to be in my vault
at Gringotts. How did you get it?
내 금고에 있어야 할 칼을
어떻게 가졌지?
What else did you and your
friends take from my vault?!
내 금고에서
또 뭘 훔쳐 갔어?
I didn't take anything. Please.
I didn't take anything.
아무것도 안 훔쳤어요
훔치지 않았어요
I don't believe it.
못 믿어
We have to do something.
구해 줘야 돼!
There's no way out of here. We've
tried everything. It's enchanted.
여길 나갈 수가 없어
주문에 걸려 있어
- Please! Please!
- Shut up!
You're bleeding, Harry.
피를 흘리잖아
That's a curious thing
to keep in your sock.
양말 속에
별걸 다 넣어 놨네
Help us.
도와주세요
- Let her go.
- Shut up. Get back.
- 걔를 보내 줘요
- 닥치고 물러서
You, goblin, come with me.
너, 도깨비
나와
- Aah!
- Dobby?
도비?
What are you doing here?
여긴 왜 왔어?
Dobby has come to rescue
Harry Potter, of course.
해리 포터를
구해 주러 왔어요
Dobby will always be
there for Harry Potter.
도비의 은인이니까요
You can Apparate in and out of this
room? Could you take us with you?
여기 밖으로 순간 이동 가능해?
우리를 데려갈 수 있어?
Of course, Sir. I'm an elf.
물론이죠, 전 요정인걸요
Works for me.
그렇게 하자
Dobby, I want you to take
Luna and Mr. Ollivander...
루나와 올리밴더 씨를…
Shell Cottage on the
outskirts of Tinworth.
조개 껍데기
오두막으로 데려가
Trust me.
날 믿어
Whenever you're ready, Sir.
우린 준비됐어요, 선생님
Sir? I like her very much.
"선생님"?
이 아가씨 참 좋아요
Meet me at the top of the
stairs in 10 seconds.
10초 후에
계단 위에서 만나요
Ow.
Who gets his wand?
이 지팡이는
누가 가질래요?
I'm only going to ask
you once more, goblin.
마지막으로
한 번만 더 묻겠다
Think very, very carefully
before you answer.
잘 생각해서
대답하는 게 좋을 거야
I don't know.
정말 몰라요
You don't know? Why weren't
you doing your job?
모른다고? 금고 지키는 게
네 일이었잖아
Who got into my vault?
누가 내 금고에 들어갔지?
Who stole it? Who stole it?
Well?
누가 훔쳤어?
누가 칼을 훔쳤느냐고!
When I was last in your
vault, the sword was there.
제가 금고에 갔을 땐
칼이 있었어요
잡종
Oh, well then, perhaps it just
walked out on it's own then.
그럼 칼이
제 발로 걸어 나왔나?
There is no place
safer than Gringotts.
거기보다 안전한 장소는
없습니다
Liar!
거짓말!
Consider yourself lucky, goblin.
운 좋은 줄 알아
죽이진 않을 테니
The same won't be
said for this one.
얘는 운이 안 좋네
Like hell.
웃기지 마!
Expellliarmus!
엑스펠리아르무스
Stupefy.
스투페파이
Stop!
그만!
Drop your wands.
지팡이를 버려
I said, drop them!
버려!
Pick them up, Draco, now.
빨리 챙겨, 드레이코
Well, well, well, look
what we have here.
이런, 이런
이게 누구야?
It's Harry Potter.
해리 포터네
He's all bright and shiny and new
again, just in time for the Dark Lord.
어둠의 마왕님을 맞으려고
깨끗한 모습으로 돌아왔군
Call him.
'그분'을 불러
어서!
Stupefy!
스투페파이
Stupid elf.
멍청한 요정!
- You could've killed me.
- Dobby never meant to kill.
- 날 죽일 뻔했잖아!
- 도비는 죽일 마음 없었어요
Dobby only meant to maim
or seriously injure.
도비는 큰 부상만
입히려고 했어요
How dare you take
a witch's wand?
감히 마녀의 지팡이를
가져가고
How dare you defy your masters?
주인에게 대들다니!
Dobby has no master.
도비한텐 주인이 없어요
Dobby is a free elf.
도비는 자유로운 요정이죠
And Dobby has come to save
Harry Potter and his friends.
도비는 해리 포터와
친구들을 구하러 왔고요!
Hermione.
헤르미온느
You're all right. We're safe.
괜찮아, 이젠 안전해
We're all safe.
모두 다 무사해
Harry Potter.
해리 포터
Dobby.
도비
Dobby. No, just... Hold on.
도비, 안돼…
조금만 참아
Hold on. Look, just
hold on, okay?
조금만 참아
죽으면 안 돼, 알았지?
We'll fix you.
우리가 고쳐 줄게
Hermione will have something.
약이 있을 거야
In your bag. Hermione?
가방에 있지? 헤르미온느?
Hermione?
헤르미온느?
What is it? Help me.
도와줘!
Such a beautiful place...
이토록 아름다운 곳에
to be with friends.
친구들과 있어 참 좋아요
Dobby is happy to be
with his friend...
도비는 친구들과 있어서
행복해요
Harry Potter.
해리 포터
We should close his eyes.
눈을 감겨 줘야지
Don't you think?
안 그래?
There.
됐어
Now he could be sleeping.
이제 편히 잘 거야
I want to bury him.
묻어 주고 싶어
Properly. Without magic.
제대로…
마법을 안 쓰고